Toggle navigation

Privacy Policy of **Kiddoware Apps and Services**
=================================================

This is our general privacy policy. Below are links to our app specific privacy policy

1. [Kids Place Privacy Policy](https://kiddoware.com//kids-place-privacy-policy/)
2. [Safe Browser Privacy Policy](https://kiddoware.com/safe-browser-privacy-policy/?lang=en)
3. [Remote Control Privacy Policy](https://kiddoware.com/kids-place-remote-control-privacy-policy/)
4. [Kids Video Player Privacy Policy](https://kiddoware.com/kids-video-player-privacy-policy/)
5. [Boby Bot Privacy Policy](https://kiddoware.com/kbot-privacy-policy/)
6. [Safe Browsing VPN Privacy Policy](https://kiddoware.com/safe-browsing-vpn-privacy-policy/)
7. [Story Creator App](https://kiddoware.com/kids-bedtime-story-creator-privacy-policy/)
8. [AI Study and Homework Assistant EdBot App](https://kiddoware.com/ai-study-and-homework-assistance-edbot-privacy-policy/)

We collect some Personal Data from its Users.

Policy summary
--------------

Personal Data collected for the following purposes and using the following services:
------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

* Analytics
    * Google Analytics with anonymized IP and Google AnalyticsPersonal Data: Cookies and Usage Data
    * Google Analytics for FirebasePersonal Data: Cookies, unique device identifiers for advertising (Google Advertiser ID or IDFA, for example) and Usage Data
    * DripPersonal Data: email address (If provided by user)
    * OneSignalPersonal Data: Cookies, email address (if provided by user), country, language, unique device identifiers for advertising (Google Advertiser ID or IDFA, for example), Usage Data and various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the servic
    * SmartLook Qualitative Analytics (Completely anonymous. No personal, PII, user id/ip address is collected)
* Contacting the User
    * Contact formPersonal Data: email address, first name and last name
    * Mailing list or newsletterPersonal Data: email address
* Content performance and features testing (A/B testing)
    * Firebase Remote ConfigPersonal Data: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service
* Device permissions for Personal Data access
    * Device permissions for Personal Data accessPersonal Data: Approximate location permission (non-continuous for Geo Fences feature in Kids Place Remote Control App), Microphone permission (For voice based actions), Phone permission (in Kids Place and Kids Phone app for blocking phone calls), Precise location permission (non-continuous for Geo Fences feature in Kids Place Remote Control App) and Storage permission
* Hosting and backend infrastructure
    * Firebase Cloud Firestore, Firebase Cloud Storage, Firebase Cloud Functions and Firebase Realtime DatabasePersonal Data: Usage Data and various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service
    * Amazon Web Services (AWS) and Google Cloud StoragePersonal Data: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service
* Infrastructure monitoring
    * Firebase Crash ReportingPersonal Data: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service
    * CrashlyticsPersonal Data: geographic position, unique device identifiers for advertising (Google Advertiser ID or IDFA, for example) and various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service
    * ACRAPersonal Data: geographic position, unique device identifier, device model, android version, error log and various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service
* Interaction with external social networks and platforms
    * social widgetsPersonal Data: Cookies and Usage Data
    * Kids Video Player uses YouTube API for searching and Playing YouTube videos. Please see YouTube terms below:  
* Location-based interactions
    * Non-continuous geolocationPersonal Data: geographic position(for Geo Fencing feature in Kids Place Remote Control App)
* Managing contacts and sending messages
    * Firebase Cloud Messaging and Firebase NotificationsPersonal Data: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service
    * DripPersonal Data: email address
* Registration and authentication
    * Firebase AuthenticationPersonal Data: email address
* Social features
    * Firebase InvitesPersonal Data: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service
    * Inviting and suggesting friendsPersonal Data: Email address and Name.

Further information about Personal Data
---------------------------------------

* Unique device identificationThis Application may track Users by storing a unique identifier of their device, for analytics purposes or for storing Users’ preferences.
* User identification via a universally unique identifier (UUID)This Application may track Users by storing a so-called universally unique identifier (or short UUID) for analytics purposes or for storing Users’ preferences. This identifier is generated upon installation of this Application, it persists between Application launches and updates, but it is lost when the User deletes the Application. A reinstall generates a new UUID.
* The Service is not directed to children under the age of 13Users declare themselves to be adult according to their applicable legislation. Minors may use this Application only with the assistance of a parent or guardian. Under no circumstance persons under the age of 13 may use this Application.
* Push notificationsThis Application may send push notifications to the User.

Contact information
-------------------

* Owner and Data ControllerKiddoware 1314 E. Calle De Arcos, Tempe, AZ, 85284, USA**Owner contact email:** kiddoware@kiddoware.com

Full policy
-----------

Owner and Data Controller
-------------------------

Kiddoware 1314 E. Calle De Arcos, Tempe, AZ, 85284, USA

**Owner contact email:** kiddoware@kiddoware.com

Types of Data collected
-----------------------

Among the types of Personal Data that this Application collects, by itself or through third parties, there are: email address, Cookies, Usage Data, unique device identifiers for advertising (Google Advertiser ID or IDFA, for example), first name, last name, Precise location permission (non-continuous), Approximate location permission (non-continuous), Microphone permission, Phone permission, Storage permission, geographic position and various types of Data.

Complete details on each type of Personal Data collected are provided in the dedicated sections of this privacy policy or by specific explanation texts displayed prior to the Data collection.  
Personal Data may be freely provided by the User, or, in case of Usage Data, collected automatically when using this Application.  
Unless specified otherwise, all Data requested by this Application is mandatory and failure to provide this Data may make it impossible for this Application to provide its services. In cases where this Application specifically states that some Data is not mandatory, Users are free not to communicate this Data without consequences to the availability or the functioning of the Service.  
Users who are uncertain about which Personal Data is mandatory are welcome to contact the Owner.  
Any use of Cookies – or of other tracking tools – by this Application or by the owners of third-party services used by this Application serves the purpose of providing the Service required by the User, in addition to any other purposes described in the present document and in the Cookie Policy, if available.

Users are responsible for any third-party Personal Data obtained, published or shared through this Application and confirm that they have the third party’s consent to provide the Data to the Owner.

Mode and place of processing the Data
-------------------------------------

### Methods of processing

The Owner takes appropriate security measures to prevent unauthorized access, disclosure, modification, or unauthorized destruction of the Data.  
The Data processing is carried out using computers and/or IT enabled tools, following organizational procedures and modes strictly related to the purposes indicated. In addition to the Owner, in some cases, the Data may be accessible to certain types of persons in charge, involved with the operation of this Application (administration, sales, marketing, legal, system administration) or external parties (such as third-party technical service providers, mail carriers, hosting providers, IT companies, communications agencies) appointed, if necessary, as Data Processors by the Owner. The updated list of these parties may be requested from the Owner at any time.

### Legal basis of processing

The Owner may process Personal Data relating to Users if one of the following applies:

* Users have given their consent for one or more specific purposes. Note: Under some legislations the Owner may be allowed to process Personal Data until the User objects to such processing (“opt-out”), without having to rely on consent or any other of the following legal bases. This, however, does not apply, whenever the processing of Personal Data is subject to European data protection law;
* provision of Data is necessary for the performance of an agreement with the User and/or for any pre-contractual obligations thereof;
* processing is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which the Owner is subject;
* processing is related to a task that is carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of official authority vested in the Owner;
* processing is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by the Owner or by a third party.

In any case, the Owner will gladly help to clarify the specific legal basis that applies to the processing, and in particular whether the provision of Personal Data is a statutory or contractual requirement, or a requirement necessary to enter into a contract.

### Place

The Data is processed at the Owner’s operating offices and in any other places where the parties involved in the processing are located.  
  
Depending on the User’s location, data transfers may involve transferring the User’s Data to a country other than their own. To find out more about the place of processing of such transferred Data, Users can check the section containing details about the processing of Personal Data.

Users are also entitled to learn about the legal basis of Data transfers to a country outside the European Union or to any international organization governed by public international law or set up by two or more countries, such as the UN, and about the security measures taken by the Owner to safeguard their Data.  
  
If any such transfer takes place, Users can find out more by checking the relevant sections of this document or inquire with the Owner using the information provided in the contact section.

### Retention time

Personal Data shall be processed and stored for as long as required by the purpose they have been collected for.

Therefore:

* Personal Data collected for purposes related to the performance of a contract between the Owner and the User shall be retained until such contract has been fully performed.
* Personal Data collected for the purposes of the Owner’s legitimate interests shall be retained as long as needed to fulfill such purposes. Users may find specific information regarding the legitimate interests pursued by the Owner within the relevant sections of this document or by contacting the Owner.

The Owner may be allowed to retain Personal Data for a longer period whenever the User has given consent to such processing, as long as such consent is not withdrawn. Furthermore, the Owner may be obliged to retain Personal Data for a longer period whenever required to do so for the performance of a legal obligation or upon order of an authority.  
  
Once the retention period expires, Personal Data shall be deleted. Therefore, the right to access, the right to erasure, the right to rectification and the right to data portability cannot be enforced after expiration of the retention period.

The purposes of processing
--------------------------

The Data concerning the User is collected to allow the Owner to provide its Services, as well as for the following purposes: Registration and authentication, Analytics, Interaction with external social networks and platforms, Hosting and backend infrastructure, Managing contacts and sending messages, Infrastructure monitoring, Social features, Content performance and features testing (A/B testing), Contacting the User, Device permissions for Personal Data access, Location-based interactions and Remarketing and behavioral targeting.

Users can find further detailed information about such purposes of processing and about the specific Personal Data used for each purpose in the respective sections of this document.

Device permissions for Personal Data access
-------------------------------------------

Depending on the User’s specific device, this Application may request certain permissions that allow it to access the User’s device Data as described below.

By default, these permissions must be granted by the User before the respective information can be accessed. Once the permission has been given, it can be revoked by the User at any time. In order to revoke these permissions, Users may refer to the device settings or contact the Owner for support at the contact details provided in the present document.  
The exact procedure for controlling app permissions may be dependent on the User’s device and software.

Please note that the revoking of such permissions might impact the proper functioning of this Application.

If User grants any of the permissions listed below, the respective Personal Data may be processed (i.e accessed to, modified or removed) by this Application.

### Approximate location permission (non-continuous)

Used for accessing the User’s approximate device location. This Application may collect, use, and share User location Data in order to provide location-based services.  
The geographic location of the User is determined in a manner that isn’t continuous. This means that it is impossible for this Application to derive the approximate position of the User on a continuous basis.

### Microphone permission

Used for accessing and recording microphone audio from the User’s device.

### Phone permission

Used for accessing a host of typical features associated with telephony. This enables, for instance, read-only access to the “phone state”, which means it enables access to the phone number of the device, current mobile network information, or the status of any ongoing calls.

### Precise location permission (non-continuous)

Used for accessing the User’s precise device location. This Application may collect, use, and share User location Data in order to provide location-based services.  
The geographic location of the User is determined in a manner that isn’t continuous. This means that it is impossible for this Application to derive the exact position of the User on a continuous basis.

### Storage permission

Used for accessing shared external storage, including the reading and adding of any items.

Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data
-------------------------------------------------------

Personal Data is collected for the following purposes and using the following services:

* Analytics
* Contacting the User
* Content performance and features testing (A/B testing)
* Device permissions for Personal Data access
* Hosting and backend infrastructure
* Infrastructure monitoring
* Interaction with external social networks and platforms
* Location-based interactions
* Managing contacts and sending messages
* Registration and authentication
* Remarketing and behavioral targeting
* Social features

Further information about Personal Data
---------------------------------------

* Unique device identification
* User identification via a universally unique identifier (UUID)
* The Service is not directed to children under the age of 13
* Push notifications

The rights of Users
-------------------

Users may exercise certain rights regarding their Data processed by the Owner.

In particular, Users have the right to do the following:

* **Withdraw their consent at any time.** Users have the right to withdraw consent where they have previously given their consent to the processing of their Personal Data.
* **Object to processing of their Data.** Users have the right to object to the processing of their Data if the processing is carried out on a legal basis other than consent. Further details are provided in the dedicated section below.
* **Access their Data.** Users have the right to learn if Data is being processed by the Owner, obtain disclosure regarding certain aspects of the processing and obtain a copy of the Data undergoing processing.
* **Verify and seek rectification.** Users have the right to verify the accuracy of their Data and ask for it to be updated or corrected.
* **Restrict the processing of their Data.** Users have the right, under certain circumstances, to restrict the processing of their Data. In this case, the Owner will not process their Data for any purpose other than storing it.
* **Have their Personal Data deleted or otherwise removed.** Users have the right, under certain circumstances, to obtain the erasure of their Data from the Owner.
* **Receive their Data and have it transferred to another controller.** Users have the right to receive their Data in a structured, commonly used and machine readable format and, if technically feasible, to have it transmitted to another controller without any hindrance. This provision is applicable provided that the Data is processed by automated means and that the processing is based on the User’s consent, on a contract which the User is part of or on pre-contractual obligations thereof.
* **Lodge a complaint.** Users have the right to bring a claim before their competent data protection authority.

### Details about the right to object to processing

Where Personal Data is processed for a public interest, in the exercise of an official authority vested in the Owner or for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by the Owner, Users may object to such processing by providing a ground related to their particular situation to justify the objection.

Users must know that, however, should their Personal Data be processed for direct marketing purposes, they can object to that processing at any time without providing any justification. To learn, whether the Owner is processing Personal Data for direct marketing purposes, Users may refer to the relevant sections of this document.

### How to exercise these rights

Any requests to exercise User rights can be directed to the Owner through the contact details provided in this document. These requests can be exercised free of charge and will be addressed by the Owner as early as possible and always within one month.

Cookie Policy
-------------

This Application uses Cookies. To learn more and for a detailed cookie notice, the User may consult the [Cookie Policy](https://www.iubenda.com/privacy-policy/98076549/cookie-policy?ifr=true&height=800&an=no).

Additional information about Data collection and processing
-----------------------------------------------------------

### Legal action

The User’s Personal Data may be used for legal purposes by the Owner in Court or in the stages leading to possible legal action arising from improper use of this Application or the related Services.  
The User declares to be aware that the Owner may be required to reveal personal data upon request of public authorities.

### Additional information about User’s Personal Data

In addition to the information contained in this privacy policy, this Application may provide the User with additional and contextual information concerning particular Services or the collection and processing of Personal Data upon request.

### System logs and maintenance

For operation and maintenance purposes, this Application and any third-party services may collect files that record interaction with this Application (System logs) use other Personal Data (such as the IP Address) for this purpose.

### Information not contained in this policy

More details concerning the collection or processing of Personal Data may be requested from the Owner at any time. Please see the contact information at the beginning of this document.

### How “Do Not Track” requests are handled

This Application does not support “Do Not Track” requests.  
To determine whether any of the third-party services it uses honor the “Do Not Track” requests, please read their privacy policies.

### Changes to this privacy policy

The Owner reserves the right to make changes to this privacy policy at any time by giving notice to its Users on this page and possibly within this Application and/or – as far as technically and legally feasible – sending a notice to Users via any contact information available to the Owner. It is strongly recommended to check this page often, referring to the date of the last modification listed at the bottom.   
  
Should the changes affect processing activities performed on the basis of the User’s consent, the Owner shall collect new consent from the User, where required.

### Definitions and legal references

Latest update: May 22, 2019

[iubenda](https://www.iubenda.com/) hosts this content and only collects [the Personal Data strictly necessary](https://www.iubenda.com/privacy-policy/877900) for it to be provided

### About Us

**Kiddoware** is the world’s leading parental control solutions company with a wide range of products and  serving over 5 million families worldwide. Kiddoware is committed in helping you to protect your kids while providing you intelligence to be proactive about your childs’ online activities.

[](https://m.facebook.com/kiddoware.parentalcontrol/)   [](https://instagram.com/kiddoware?utm_medium=copy_link)   [

](https://twitter.com/kiddoware)   [

](https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCjdnpIusMJ-4yOk0cdnVJfw)

### Products

### Support

Delightful deal: Get 20% off our top-rated parental control app! **20% Off.**  

This is default text for notification bar

Learn more

[](javascript:void(0))[](javascript:void(0))

[](javascript:void(0))
